daft.ie 2014-12-29

# Daft.ie : Information

**About us**  
**What our Privacy Policy Covers**  
**Introduction**  
**Personal information collected**  
**Who has access to the information you provide or we collect?**  
**Cookies and tracking**  
**Anti-Spam Policy**

## About us

Websites within the Daft Media Group hereafter known as the "Site" provide an online information service. Our service allows advertisers to display properties they are marketing for sale or rent. We are not estate agents. Daft Media Ltd, ("Daft"), has offices in Latin Hall, Golden Lane, Dublin 8. Our Company Registration Number is 347856. 

## What our Privacy Policy Covers

This Privacy Policy covers any personal information the Site obtains from you when you use our service. This policy does not cover the practices of companies that Daft does not own or control, or the actions of people that Daft does not employ or manage. 

Our Privacy Policy may change in the future. We invite you to check back periodically to see if we have made any changes. By using this site, you agree to the terms of our policy. 

## Introduction

At Daft we are committed to protecting your privacy. This policy explains how and for what purposes we use the information collected about you via the Site. Please read this privacy policy carefully. By using this Site and any services we offer via this Site, you are agreeing to be bound by this policy in respect of the information collected about you via this Site. 

If you have any queries or comments about the policy or our use of your personal information, please get in touch with us by emailing us at [supportdesk@daft.ie](mailto:supportdesk@daft.ie) or writing to The Privacy Department at Latin Hall, Golden Lane, Dublin 8. 

In general, we use the information we collect about you to: 

  * improve the features and services we offer 
  * help our members provide more personalised services to you 
  * support our own marketing and promotion efforts. 

## Personal information collected

When you visit, register or use the services on this Site, you may be asked to provide certain information about yourself, including your name and your contact details. We may also collect information about how you use this Site including your searches, the properties you look at, agents or developers you contact and the contents of the emails you send to them. Finally, we may also collect information from any correspondence that you have with us. 

### Information collection and use

Your information will enable us to provide you with access to all parts of this Site and to supply the services and features that you have requested. We may aggregate the information to identify patterns which we can use in our marketing and to help us develop, administer, support and improve our services and features. 

We may use your information to contact you for your views on our services and to notify you occasionally about important changes or developments to this Site or our services. Where you have consented, we might also use your information to email you with details about any other products or services which we offer which may be of interest to you. If you change your mind about being contacted in the future, please email us at [supportdesk@daft.ie](mailto:supportdesk@daft.ie) and tell us. 

The following features, by their nature, require and make use of personally identifiable information. 

### Sending emails

The information that you complete on the 'Email Advertiser' forms on this Site is recorded by us and is sent to the advertiser that you wish to contact. This helps them provide you with a more personalised service. 

### Email a Friend

When you use the 'email a friend' feature of this Site we record which properties you have sent to the friend, solely so that we can track the popularity of those properties. We record the other details provided in the email for internal monitoring of the service. We will not add any information collected in this manner to our mailing lists to protect you and the recipient's privacy. 

### Registering with us

You do not need to register with us to visit our web pages. If you do register with us, we save the details you provide and use them to enable us to personalise the service we offer to you. You can update your details at any time via the site. 

## Who has access to the information you provide or we collect?

We retain access to all personal information that we have collected from you. 

If you have consented on signup or the appropriate email form, we may provide any of the information we collect to carefully screened third parties to contact you regarding products or services that we think may be of interest to you. If you change your mind about being contacted by these third parties in the future, please email us at [supportdesk@daft.ie](mailto:supportdesk@daft.ie) and tell us. 

If our business enters into a joint venture with or is sold to or merged with another business entity, your information may be disclosed to our new business partners or owners. 

We use third party analytics services to help understand your use of our services. Google Analytics combines information from Google's interest-based advertising or 3rd-party audience data to provide approximate demographic information. We provide a limited amount of your information (such as your sign-up date and username) to Intercom, Inc. ("Intercom") and we use Intercom to collect data for analytics purposes when you visit our website or use or product. Intercom analyzes your use of our website and/or product and our relationship with you, so that we can improve our service to you. We may also use Intercom as a medium or communications, either through email, or through messages within our product(s). Also as part of their service to us, Intercom collects publicly available contact and social information related to you, such as your email address, gender, company, job title, photos, website URLs, social network handles and physical addresses, so that we can continue to improve our relationship with you. For more information on the privacy practices of Intercom, please check [http://docs.intercom.io/privacy](https://docs.intercom.io/privacy). Intercom's services are governed by Intercom's terms of use which can be found at [http://docs.intercom.io/terms](https://docs.intercom.io/terms). 

If you would like to opt out of having this information collected by or submitted to Intercom, please contact us. 

We will not otherwise disclose, sell or distribute your information to any third party without your permission unless we are required to do so by law. 

###  Access to, changing or removing the information we hold 

Registered users of this Site can update their information or change their settings once signed in. Registered users can cancel their membership by contacting [supportdesk@daft.ie](mailto:supportdesk@daft.ie). 

Non-registered and registered users of this Site can request we provide them with a copy of the personally identifiable information we hold via [supportdesk@daft.ie](mailto:supportdesk@daft.ie). You may ask us to make any necessary changes to ensure that such information is accurate and kept up-to-date. We may charge a small administration fee to cover the data search, preparation and delivery. 

## Cookies and tracking

Like many websites, we use "cookies" to enable us to personalise your visits to this website, simplify the signing-in procedure, keep track of your preferences and to track the usage of this website. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored in the hard drive of your computer by your browser. Your browser will have the option to prevent websites using cookies (your browser's help screen or manual will tell you how to do this), but please note that this may reduce the functionality of this Site and other websites. 

Like all websites, our servers automatically record 'log files' containing information about the volume and characteristics of our website traffic e.g. IP address, numbers of pages viewed, length of time spent on site. We use log files to build pictures of how our site is used that help us to monitor and improve the service. We cannot identify you from your log files. 

If you are primarily concerned about third party cookies generated by advertisers, you can turn these off by going to <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/ie/>

Here is a list of all the cookies that we set and how we use them: 

Cookie Name | Typical Value | Purpose | Expires  
---|---|---|---  
daftID | Randomly generated alphanumeric string | Used to identify user session | On browser exit  
unique | Date and randomly generated alphanumeric string | Used for comparison with other "unique" cookies to decide unique visits to site | Jan 1st, 6 years after visit  
strap_*_* | The number "1" | Ensure a strapline won't be seen after being dismissed | 3 years  
adserver_ccid | "roi", "ni", "c1"-"c32", "ct1"-"ct6" | Remembers the last county/city/general area searched so it's recalled in subsequent searches | End of following year  
cookie_user_id | User ID | Set only if "Remember me" is checked. Auto-login on subsequent visits. | On user log out  
cookie_uid | User ID | Set only if "Remember me" is checked. Auto-login on subsequent visits. | On user log out  
cookie_notice | 1 |  Whether the user has seen the sitewide notice regarding the use of cookies on Daft.ie.  | 1 year from being set  
daft_last_search | Json representation of last search filters used |  Used to generate the recently searched properties for the homepage  | 1 month from being set  
dgo | 1 |  Used to signify that a mobile user does not wish the site to open in the app  | 1 month from being set  
daft_uuid | Randomly generated alphanumeric string | Used to identify user session | Jan 1st, 6 years after visit  
  
In addition to the above cookies set by Daft, cookies may also be set by a number of our site partners. 

Google Analytics (Audience Measurement)   
---  
__utma | Randomly generated number | Usage stats | 2 years  
__utmb | Randomly generated number | Usage stats | 30 minutes  
__utmc | Randomly generated number | Usage stats | On browser exit  
__utmz | Randomly generated number | Usage stats | 6 months  
Comscore (Audience Measurement)   
UID | Hexadecimal-ip-numerical | User id | 1 year, 354 days  
UIDR | Numerical (same as end of UID) | Real user id | 1 year, 354 days  
pool.distilled.ie (Network Targeting)   
__cfduid | Hexadecimal-ip-numerical | User identifier | 6 years  
  
We also use third party advertisements to support our site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on our site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP, the browser you used to visit our site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. This is generally used for geotargeting purposes (showing France property adverts to someone in Paris, for example) or showing certain ads based on specific sites visited (such as showing cooking ads to someone who frequents cooking sites). 

### DoubleClick DART cookies

We also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google's DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests ("interest based targeting"). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history (For example, if you have been viewing sites about visiting Las Vegas, you may see Las Vegas hotel advertisements when viewing a non-related site, such as on a site about hockey). DART uses "non personally identifiable information". It does NOT track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, physical address, telephone number, social security numbers, bank account numbers or credit card numbers. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting <http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx>

### Security, storage and transfer of information

We follow strict security procedures to ensure that your personal information is not damaged, destroyed, or disclosed to a third party without your permission (unless they are providing services as outlined in the 'who has access to your information' section above) and to prevent unauthorised access to it. The computers that store the information are kept in a secure facility with restricted physical access and we use secure firewalls and other measures to restrict electronic access. If we are working with third parties we will require them to have in place similar measures to protect your information. 

All of the information we collect or record is restricted to our offices. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information. We will explicitly ask you when we need information to identify you. We may require you to co-operate with our security checks before we disclose information to you. You can update the personal information that you give us at any time by viewing your details page. 

We will retain your information for a reasonable period or for as long as is required by law. 

## Anti-Spam Policy

This Anti-Spam Policy Notice governs the use of the web page at and its associated services, web pages, domains and sub-domains, which are owned and operated by Daft. The Site should not be used as a database for direct marketing by phone or SMS messaging. The personal contact details contained in the placements on this site are for the sole purpose of letting or selling a property and should not be used for any other purpose. It is an offence to send unsolicited direct marketing text messages or make unsolicited marketing phone calls. Each such call or message may be punished by a fine of up to €5,000. 

We consider spamming to be any activity whereby you directly or indirectly transmit email messages to any email address that has not solicited such email and does not consent to such transmission. We also consider spamming to constitute posting advertisements that are off topic, or in discussion forums that do not specifically permit advertisements. 

We reserve the right to terminate your account if we deem you to be in violation of our anti-spamming policies. We also reserve the right to suspend your account pending review upon receipt of any complaint or other evidence that you may be engaging in any spamming activity. 

If you are "spammed" by any products, services, website, or any other matters, please report this activity to [supportdesk@daft.ie](mailto:supportdesk@daft.ie)
